Guide to the Russell and Sigurd Varian Papers
Stanford University Libraries.
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives.
Russell and Sigurd Varian papers
1836-1988
SC0345
Varian, Russell Harrison, 1898-1959
Varian, Sigurd Fergus, 1901-1961
26 Linear feet
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives. Stanford University Libraries. 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: speccollref@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Biography
Russsell and Sigurd Varian were co-inventors, with William W. Hansen, of the klystron and rhumbatron and co-founders of Varian Associates. Educated at Stanford University, physicist and inventor Russell Varian began his career with Philo Farnsworth on early television technology and with Humble Oil on instrumentation for oil exploration. In 1935, he returned to Stanford. Joined by his brother, Sigurd, a pilot with Pan American Airlines, he began work on microwave technology as a research assistant with Professor William Hansen. The klystron patent brought both financial gain to the University and the attention of federal research agencies, while leading to the formation of Varian Associates, one of California's first Silicon Valley companies.
Scope and Content
The Varian papers span almost a hundred years of creative and independent thinking, from early manuscripts of poetry by John O. Varian, to the creation and growth of Varian Associates. In addition to original research notebooks and correspondence regarding the klystron, the papers of Russell and Sigurd Varian include materials on numerous other inventions and ideas from Russell's work for Philo Farnsworth and Humble Oil as well as the brothers' years at Stanford and at Varian Associates. Unpublished short stories by Sigurd reveal his sense of humor as well as the adventure and danger of his career as a pilot in Mexico and Central America.
The Varian Papers also contain correspondence, diaries, and writings of other family members including Dorothy Varian, Agnes Dickson Varian, Aileen Dickson Harrison, and Eric Varian. The letters and diaries of Agnes Dickson Varian pertain to family and community life in Palo Alto and Halcyon, California; Dorothy Varian's papers include her research files used to prepare her biography of Russell and Sigurd Varian as well as correspondence, talks, and other papers pertaining to environmental issues. There is also a series containing photographs documenting the family, Varian Associates, and the history of the klystron.
Access Terms
Cowell, Henry,, 1819-; Farnsworth, Philo.; Ginzton, Edward L. (Edward Leonard), 1915-; Hansen, W. W. (William Webster), 1909-1949; Humble Oil and Refining Company (Incorporated in Tex.).; Stanford University. Department of Physics.; Varian Associates..; Varian, Agnes.; Varian, Eric.; Varian, John.; Varian, Russell Harrison, 1898-1959; Varian, Sigurd Fergus,, 1901-1961.; Aeronautics.; American literature--20th century.; Halcyon (Calif.); Journals.; Klystrons.; Microelectronics industry--California--Santa Clara County.; Palo Alto (Calif.); Physics.; Science--History.
Collection Contents
- Russell H. Varian Papers, 1915-1966; Series 1
  Professional and personal correspondence, research notebooks, scientific writings and publications, speeches, patent records, personal writings, and biographical materials.
  Earned his BA in physics at Stanford in 1925 and his MA in 1927, fellow student was Bill Hansen. He went to work for Farnsworth Television Laboratory, producing at least 11 patentable devices. In 1933 he returned to Stanford to continue his graduate work in physics.
  1898 Born 1903 Family moved to Palo Alto 1914 family moved to Halcyon, CA 1919 started at Stanford 1925 BA 1927 MA 1935- graduate work 1935 sets up laboratory in Halcyon with Sig and Eric 1937 Feb. return to Stanford to work on radar 1937 Aug. 19 & 21 first oscillating klystron tests 1939, Jan. first successful test of Klystron [or invention of klystron announced to public] 1940 fall work for Sperry Gyroscope 1946 returned to Stanford 1948 founding of Varian Associates 1950 move of Varian Associates to Stanford Industrial Park 1959 died
  - Professional Papers
    - Correspondence
      - Outgoing, 1929-1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Outgoing, 1919-1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Outgoing, 1941 and circa 1941 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Outgoing, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Outgoing, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Outgoing, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Outgoing, 1947-1949 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Outgoing, 1950-1956 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Outgoing, 1957-59 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Incoming, A - J, 1939-1957 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Incoming, K - Z, 1939-1959 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Incoming, Farnsworth Television Inc., 1935-1939 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Incoming, Frankling Institute, 1950-53 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Incoming, Hansen, William W., 1936-1939 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Incoming, Hunter, Paul, 1938-1948 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Incoming, International Science Foundation, 1957-58 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Incoming, Jenkins, Richard L., 1957-58 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Incoming, Leonard, Richard M., 1956-1959 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Incoming, Mattill, John I., 1948 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Incoming, Miranda Lux Foundation, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Incoming, National Defense Research Committee, 1941-1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Incoming, Newkirk, Wallace, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Incoming, re: patents, 1936-1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Incoming, Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn, 1958-59 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Incoming, Rines, David, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Incoming, Sperry Gyroscope, 1939-1953 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Incoming, Stanford University, miscellaneous, 1938-1944 and undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Incoming, Stanford University, Office of the Business Manager, 1948-1950 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Incoming, Stanford University, Office of the Business Manager, 1951-1957 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Incoming, re: Stanford scholarships, 1956-1959 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Incoming, War Production Board/War Dept., 1942-1943 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Incoming, Webster, David L., 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Biographical Material
      - Awards: Institute of Radio Engineers, 1951-1959 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Awards: James Forrestal Memorial Award, 1958-1960 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Awards: Miscellaneous, 1938-1955 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Biographical material (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Honorary degree: Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Travel expense reports, 1957-1959 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Research Files
      - Research notes, rectilinear motion, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Research notes, reduction of iron, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Research notes, resonant magnetometers (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Research notes while at Sperry Gyroscope (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Research notes and drawings while at Sperry Gyroscope (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Notebook from Television Laboratories, 1931-1933 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Notebook (typescript copy), 1937-1940 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Notebook, 1946-1948 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Notebook, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Research notes (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Research notes (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Research notes (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Research notes (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Research notes (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Research notes (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Research notes (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous notes (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Klystron drawings (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous drawings (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous drawings (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Writings And Speeches
      - Boiling Liquid Cooling of Solid Surfaces, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Circuits for using Webber accelerometers in autopilots, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Development of the Klystron (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Devices for generation of hyper-frequencies (Sperry research) (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Electrostatic suspension of a gyroscope (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Evolution and human behavior (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Fabricating precision tubing (Sperry research) (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Floating bearing idea (Sperry research), 1941 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Frictionless rotor, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Ground speed indicator (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - Invention, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - Invention, processes of: a case history, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - Klystron grids (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - Magnetic submarine locator (Sperry research) (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - Noise in Klystrons (Sperry research) (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - Photoelectric sextant (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - Rotating systems which are not gyroscopes, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - Traffic control device (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - Variable stroke pump (Sperry research) (Box 4, Folder 24)
      - Aphorism about pure science, Gordon Industrial Research Conference (speech), 1950 (Box 4, Folder 25)
      - Klystron, outline of talk, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 26)
      - Political implications of atomic energy (speech) (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - Varian Associates (talks), 1951-1959 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Patent Records
      - Convection inclinometer (#600, 593), 1947 (Box 4, Folder 29)
      - Docket #74 (Box 4, Folder 30)
      - Docket #87 (Box 4, Folder 31)
      - Docket #122 (Box 4, Folder 32)
      - Electron beam apparatus (#472, 788), 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 33)
      - Financial, 1938-1946 (Box 4, Folder 34)
      - Haeff v. Varian & Packard, 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 35)
      - Hahn v. Varian (Box 4, Folder 36)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Object detecting and locating system, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Oscillation generators (#412, 918), circa 1941 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Patents issued (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Stable platform, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Bibliography cards, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Bird Navigation, 1948-1955 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Conference materials, 1950-1959 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Development of the Acceleron; Sperry Gyroscope report by B. Berkowitz, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - I.R.E. Electronics Committee. Review on UHF vacuum tubes, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Klystron agreements, 1938-1941 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Klystron: articles, correspondence, press releases (not by Russell H. Varian) (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - Klystron: NBC radio program script, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Klystron Research Group, minutes, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Klystron: Sales Engineering Bulletin, Sperry Gyroscope Company, Nov-41 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - Proposed development of nuclear induction apparatus for measuring weak magnetic fields (Proposal to ONR).; "The Nuclear Induction Experiment" (Physical Review reprint); Varian Associates special products - Model F-6 Nuclear Fluxmeter. (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - Stability of an electrostatic suspension, E. Feenberg, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Stanford, agreements with, 1937-1946 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - Stanford, Dept. of Physics, directory, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Publications
      - "A Contribution to the Theory of Barrier Layer Cells,", 1934 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - "A Gas-Filled X-Ray Tube of Small Diameter and Large Power Capacity,", 1929 (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - "A High Frequency Oscillator and Amplifiers" (with Sigurd F. Varian), 1939 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - "On the Invention of the Klystron and the Founding of Varian Associates,", 1966 (Box 5, Folder 23)
      - "Quantitative Measurements on the Compton Effect in the Region of Soft X-Rays," Stanford University master's thesis, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 24)
      - "Recent Developments in Klystrons,", 1952 (Box 5, Folder 25)
      - "Remarks on:, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Varian Associates
      - Board of Directors, minutes, 1951-1953 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Executive Committee, minutes, 1951-1954 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Articles of Incorporation, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Personal Papers
    - Correspondence
      - Outgoing, 1915-1917 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Outgoing, 1919-1920 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Outgoing, 1921 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Outgoing, 1922-1923 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Outgoing, 1924-1925 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Outgoing, 1926 Jan-Mar (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Outgoing, 1926 Apr-May (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Outgoing, 1926 Jun-Aug (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Outgoing, 1926 Sep-Dec (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Outgoing, 1927 Jan-Jul (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Outgoing, 1927 Aug-Dec (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Outgoing, 1928 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Outgoing, 1929 Jan-Aug (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - Outgoing, 1929 Sep-Dec (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - Outgoing, 1930 Jan-Mar (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - Outgoing, 1930 Apr-Jul (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - Outgoing, 1930 Aug-Dec (Box 7, Folder 17)
      - Outgoing, 1931 (Box 7, Folder 18)
      - Outgoing, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 19)
      - Outgoing, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 20)
      - Outgoing, fragment, circa 1933 (Box 7, Folder 21)
      - Outgoing, 1934-1935 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Outgoing, 1946-1947 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Outgoing, no date or date unclear (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Outgoing to Sigurd F. Varian, 1928-1931 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Outgoing to Sigurd F. Varian, 1932-1933 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Outgoing to Sigurd F. Varian, 1934-1935 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Outgoing to Sigurd F. Varian, 1939-1946 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Outgoing to Sigurd F. Varian, 1947-1948 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Outgoing to Sigurd F. Varian, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Incoming, A - F (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Incoming, Cowell, Henry, 1916-1919 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Incoming, G - L (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Incoming, M - Z (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Incoming, Varian, John and Agnes (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Incoming, unidentified (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Writings
      - Dogma, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - Echo Lake Avalanches (Box 8, Folder 17)
      - Interior and Insular Affairs Hearing on S-4028, statement (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - Pelicans and Swallows (story) (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - Specialization, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 20)
      - Taking the Next Step (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - Theory about motion sickness, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 22)
      - Verses (Box 8, Folder 23)
      - Varian Associates Magazine, articles, 1956-1959 (Box 8, Folder 24)
      - The Wilderness World (Box 8, Folder 25)
      - The World of Mountains (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Biographical Materials
      - Arroyo Grande High School, grade report and diploma, 1918-1919 (Box 8, Folder 27)
      - Stanford University transcripts, 1919-1928 (Box 8, Folder 28)
      - Children's trusts, 1955-1957 (Box 8, Folder 29)
      - Financial papers, 1938-1958 (Box 8, Folder 30)
      - Miscellaneous personal papers, 1942-1946 (Box 8, Folder 31)
      - Statement: Interior and Insular Affairs Hearing on S-4028 (Box 8, Folder 32)
      - Irish Ballads, 8.33; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Additional Papers
    - Correspondence, 1941-1953 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Publications, clippings (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Boy Scout clippings (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Clippings and press releases (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Klystron Working Group, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Stanford University correspondence, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - W. W. Hansen/Reamer (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Ginzton research on Klystron (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Stanford/Klystron (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Webster/Hansen - correspondence re Klystron, 1930s-1940s (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - W.W. Hansen files (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Reports on Glass (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - W.W. Hansen, A type of electrical resonator, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Hickman, Kenneth, The high-vacuum still in medicine, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Hickman, K.C.D. and E. Leb. Gray, Molecular distillation examination of natural vitamin d., 1938 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Hickman, Kenneth C.D., Trends in design of fractionating pumps, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Hollman, Hans E., Nonlinear elements and some applications in AF and RF circuits, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Hollman, Hans E., Polaresistivity and polaristors, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Olive, Theodore R., Molecular distillation: a new path to the separation of chemicals, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Research for industry: A news bulletin from SRI, 1950 Jul (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Review of scientific instruments, 1949 Mar (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Shockley, William, Path to conception of the junction transistor., 1976 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Sperry engineering review, 1948 Jul (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Strong, Edward K., Jr., Classification of occupations by interests, 1934 Apr (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Sperryscope, 1943 Jul (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Webster, David L., Velocity-modulation currents, 1942 Dec (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Ginzton, E.L., Microwaves (part 1), 1958 Sep/Oct (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - D'Eustachio, D., Surface layers on quartz and topaz, 1946 Oct (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Dingley, Edward Nelson, Jr., A 500 cycle blind landing system, 1939 Jul (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Bloom, Arnold L., Optical pumping, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Echo gives height to RF airplanes, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Field test successful, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Four Stanford physicists improve short-wave radio, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Genius Varian brothers give Ryan a tube with a Greek name (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Ginzton, Edward L., Klystron, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Ginzton, Edward L., The $100 idea, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Hansen, W.W., and R.D. Richtmeyer, On resonators suitable for klystron oscillators, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Henderson, W.J., Jr., Greeks had a word for it (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Kylstron discovery incidental to search for atom-smasher (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Klystron's first test is a success, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Klystron tube's 25 years old (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Miscellaneous photocopies (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - MIT physicist will study uses of klystron, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Moulic, WIlliam E., Klystron characteristics, 1944 Jun (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - New radio device may save countless lives, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Naughton, Thomas J., Now...power is broadcast, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Radio waves do a rhumba, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Sperry to take a Klystron, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Stanford's Klystron makes the headlines (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Suit discloses U.S. Navy 'robot' (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Taylor, Frank J., Klystron boys, 1941 Feb (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - 3 men and a tube, 1943 Jul (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - On the 25th anniversary of the Klystron, 1962 Jun (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - The U.S. electronics industry's contribution to national defense, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Varian brother's success (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Varian, Russell and Sigurd F. Varian, A high frequency oscillator and amplifier, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - Webster, David L., Cathode-ray bunching, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 46)
    - Webster, David L., Theory of Klystron oscillations, 1939 Dec (Box 10, Folder 47)
- Sigurd F. Varian Papers, 1904-1972; Series 2
  Professional and personal correspondence, research notes and subject files, scientific writings, patent records, autobiographical writings and short stories, and biographical materials.
  Worked for California Edison after graduating from high school and soon became entranced by flying. He became a pilot 1923, flew in air meets and in air stunts during county fairs. He took a job as a flying serviceman for Southern Sierras Power Company. A prolonged bout of tuberculosis sidelined him for a year in 1928; after that he was employed by Pan American as a pilot on their Mexican and Central American routes.
  Sigurd and Russell had always collaborated on their scientific and technical ideas, with Sigurd often the one to design and build the apparatus.
  1901 Born in Syracuse, NY 1903 Family moved to Palo Alto 1914 family moved to Halcyon, CA 1923 became a pilot 1929 Married Winifred Hogg 1929-35 flight captain for Pan American Airways 1937 Aug. 19 & 21 first successful tests of oscillating klystron 1939, Jan. invention of klystron announced to public 1940 fall work for Sperry Gyroscope 1948 founding of Varian Associates 1961 died in plane crash in Mexico
  Russell and Sigurd F. Varian were the two oldest sons of John O. Varian and Agnes Dickson Varian. John O. Varian, an Irish-born poet and playwright, moved the family from New York to Palo Alto, California in 1903. Although the family’s economic earnings were modest, their home was a gathering place for writers, musicians, and social reformers. In 1914, the family moved again to Halcyon, California, where John and Agnes Varian operated a general store and post office. Russell Varian, born in 1898, began his undergraduate career at Stanford University in 1919, earning his B.A. in physics in 1925 and his M.A. in 1927. He worked with Philo Farnsworth on early television technology and with Humble Oil on instrumentation for oil exploration before returning to Stanford in 1935 to continue his graduate work in physics.
  Sigurd F. Varian, born in 1901, worked for California Edison after graduating from high school. He soon became entranced by flying. He became a pilot in 1923, flying in air meets and doing air stunts during county fairs. He took a job as a flying serviceman for Southern Sierras Power Company. A prolonged bout of tuberculosis sidelined him for a year in 1928; in 1929 he was employed by Pan American as a pilot on their Mexican and Central American routes.
  Sigurd and Russell had always collaborated on their scientific and technical ideas, with Sigurd often the one to design and build the apparatus. In 1935 Sigurd, Russell and their brother Eric started their own laboratory in Halcyon.
  - Professional Papers
    - Correspondence
      - Outgoing, 1937-1948 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Outgoing, 1949-1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Incoming, A - P, 1937-1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Incoming, R - Z and unidentified, 1939-1959 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Incoming, David L. Webster, 1939-1959 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Incoming, Hugh Willis, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Incoming re: Medical gun, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Incoming re: Microdrill, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Incoming re: patents, 1944-Mar 1949 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Incoming re: patents, Aug 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Incoming re: patents, 1952-1957 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Research
      - Notebook, circa 1935 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Notes and drawings, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Notebook, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Notes, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Notes and lab procedures, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Drawings, circa 1938-1944 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Drawings, Microwave Laboratory, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Writings And Speeches
      - Air traffic control, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Anti-collision device, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Assorted science topics, 1934 and undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Barbecue invention, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Development of the Klystron (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Gas engine (fragment), undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Magnetoabsorption equipment, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Medical gun, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Medical gun, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Speech (draft) on ultra high frequency and its use to pilots, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Patent Records
      - Interferences, data sheets, drawings, 1950-1953 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Disclosure re automatic recorder of the height of clouds, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 2)